-[insects chirping]
-[rumbling]
[dinosaurs bellowing]
[thudding]
[roars, screeches]
[Darius] Seriously, Dad,
you got to see this!
[chuckles]
Slow down, kiddo!
One day, I might need to use
this hand again.
Someone just posted
Dr. Grant's latest article
to the Jurassic World forums,
and apparently,
it says there's all this new evidence
of craniofacial biting in theropods!
Well, that would mean theropods
didn't just fight to kill,
they fought for dominance,
for power, and--
And even for fun!
-Uh, it's... it's the next paragraph down.
-Darius, let your old man read.
-[giggling]
-I sacrificed a hand for this.
I mean, can you imagine two T. rex
battling each other? [roars]
I mean, I can't even wait to see
one T. rex at Jurassic World.
Oh, we'll be there soon enough, kiddo.
Then we'll see all these big guys
for real.
[giggling]
Okay, I was gonna wait till later
to give you this,
but no time like the present
for a present. Dun-dun!
-[chuckles]
-Ain't no pun like a Dad pun.
[gasps]
Wow!
Matching raptor teeth?
[gasps]
This is so freaking cool!
[clears throat]
Uh, are you okay?
I'm fine, just a little tired.
Hey, come here.
We're going to Jurassic World
and it's gonna be incredible,
not just because of the dinosaurs,
because it'll be the two of us there,
together.
I promise.
[birds, insects chirping]
[helicopter blades whirring]
And despite the park's owner
Mr. Masrani just now arriving,
we have something that we urgently need
to discuss with you, Ms. Dearing.
-You see-- Shh!
-Don't forget about the raptor pen.
-I know, I know.
-Or the kids getting lost in the storm.
The point is--
-Or the stampede during the storm.
-Shush!
The point is, Claire, uh, Ms. Dearing,
uh, we know that Camp Cretaceous
is very important to Mr. Masrani,
and that you were thinking of having
your nephews join us today,
but we've had two serious incidents
over the last 48 hours.
Dave and I need more staff immediately
or we need to send the kids home ASAP.
[voicemail] The mailbox
you are trying to reach is full.
-Please try again later.
-[both] Ugh!
New plan: we do this in person.
Mm...
I'm sorry, are you saying
we leave the kids here alone?
Our kids?
The kids who seem determined
to get themselves trampled and/or eaten?
Those are the kids of which you speak?
We won't be gone long.
If we leave now, we can be back
in an hour or two, tops.
-[scoffs] I'll leave a note.
-[engine starts]
What up, Camp Cretaceous?
-Whoo-hoo!
-[Ben slurps]
Not in a "whoo-hoo" mood this morning,
Darius.
Not after yesterday.
Trekking through a rainstorm will do that.
We only had to walk because you crashed
our gyrosphere. [slurps]
[growls]
Mm!
But today's a new day! Kayak Day!
Who doesn't wanna paddle
alongside dinosaurs, real dinosaurs?
It's gonna be awesome, right?
Wait, where are Dave and Roxie?
The babysitters took off early
and left this.
"BRB. Gotta go. Boss-talk. BB. Later.
Smiley face."
Is that a dinosaur emoji
with a thumbs up?
It's Dave speak.
Roxie translated on the back.
"We have to go talk to our boss.
Stay inside until we return.
Draw, bond, whatever.
The radio's set for channel six
in case you need us.
Stay inside, stay inside.
Do not leave, Kenji, looking at you."
[chuckles]
Uh... "Sorry for the kids' menus,
it's all Dave had."
[Kenji] Do they understand how old we are?
I mean, when was the last time
you even saw a crayon?
Hmm. I have notes.
-Yasmina! [gasps]
-[thud]
Brooklynn. What's new on the Internet,
superstar?
I wouldn't know
because when I went to get my phone
from its charger, it wasn't there!
Someone stole my phone.
Brooklynn, who hasn't had your phone?
I needed to check the weather
last night...
Dr. Sattler posted a new column
on microfossils yesterday...
...too good to miss the selfie opp,
but I haven't used it since then, I swear!
[scoffs]
I... haven't seen it either.
-Really?
-Hey, hey, it's okay!
Since we're not kayaking till later,
we'll have plenty of time
to look for the phone.
Oh, I think I know exactly where to look.
I also think that whoever took the phone
might be trying to hide some of the things
that are on it.
What do you think, Sammy?
Um, what?
What is your deal?
Sammy said she didn't touch it!
Ever think you might have just lost
the stupid thing?
Hmm. Well, then, let's check her bags
and test that theory out.
You do not get to go through
anyone's stuff,
I don't care how famous you think you are!
-Brooklynn, I did not--
-Brooklynn, guys, come on!
We can't be this upset over phones.
Let's make the most
of this incredible opportunity!
-This is Jurassic World! It's-- It's--
-[dinosaur roars]
What was that?
-Um, a T. rex?
-Mm-mm. I don't think so.
[Ben] Then what sort of dinosaur
did it sound like?
Friend-ish? Or foe-ish?
Where's it comin' from?
Can't see anything from here.
The trees are blocking everything.
Maybe they're moving a new dino
from the lab to another enclosure.
[gasps] We could probably see it
from the observation tower! Could be cool.
[gasps] Wow, that's a great idea, Darius!
What are we waiting for?
[Brooklynn] Hey, we're not done talking
about this yet!
But, guys,
it's Indoor Arts and Crafts Day!
We should stay and wait for Dave
and Roxie, right, Kenji?
If you wanna stay here and draw you
and your dino-crush, go for it.
I'm gonna go see me a T. rex
or a girl-fight.
Either way, I win. Ka-ching!
Fine, go on! I'll just stay
where we're supposed to stay,
wait for who we're supposed to wait for,
and be right where we're supposed to be.
[whimpers]
[exhales]
[yelling] Wait! Guys, I'm coming too!
[pants]
[walkie beeps, static crackles]
[male voice] Asset out of containment.
Repeat, asset out of containment.
Stay indoors. ACU is responding.
[beeps]
[birds, insects chirping]
[grunting]
-It's locked!
-Oh, wow. Guess we can't get in.
We should all go back before someone
comes along and we get in trouble.
-[chuckles nervously]
-Wait, where is everybody?
Uh, there's usually someone around.
If we're doing this...
then we might as well do this.
Ta-da!
What? You didn't see
my "Unboxing Kathmandu" video,
"Hacks For When You Lock Yourself Out
Of Your Hotel Room"?
Last to the top is a rotten egg!
[Yasmina] Later, rotten egg.
[Sammy panting]
Is anybody else hot?
It is hot.
[all panting]
No more stairs! [pants]
-There better be something good.
-[rumbling]
[rumbling continues]
-There's something out there.
-Something big.
[gasps]
[bellowing]
-[all sighing]
-It's just a brachiosaurus.
Ooh! Mystery solved.
Guess we should head back now.
But that doesn't make any sense.
Brachiosauruses don't roar like that.
They're more like... [imitates bellowing]
Didn't quite catch that.
Uh, one more time?
[man 1] Hey! What are you kids
doin' outside?
There's an asset out of containment!
-What are they saying?
-[man 2] You can't be up there!
Oh, great! They look mad.
I told you we'd get in trouble.
Can you hear us?
You need to get down now!
-Hurry!
-You're gonna have to speak up!
-The park's going on lockdown!
-I got this.
[roaring]
[all scream]
Why aren't ya movin'?
You dumb kids, get down here right--
-[roaring]
-[screaming]
-[crunching]
-[all scream]
[roaring]
What is that?
It got him! It got him!
[gasps] Dr. Wu's lab.
-There was a dinosaur. In--
-[whispers] Indominus Rex.
How do you know that name?
-But there's no dinosaur named--
-There's no time. We need to leave.
Now, now, now! We have to go.
Up here is safe, down there isn't.
Besides, this high up, it's not like
Whatever-Rex there can even see us.
[growls, snarls]
-[all screaming]
-[Ben] It sees us!
[all gasping]
-[roars]
-[all scream]
[grunts]
[roars]
-[screaming]
-[screams, whimpers]
[metal creaking]
[Sammy] Whoa! [screams]
-Sammy!
-[screaming]
[roaring]
-[Darius] Hold on!
-[grunting]
-[crashing]
-[all] Whoa!
[grunts]
The zip line. Go, go, go!
[Ben whimpers]
[roars]
-I can't! I can't! I can't.
-[Kenji groans] Here!
[screaming]
[grunting]
[roars]
[all] Whoa!
[screaming]
-Guys?!
-[all screaming]
Whoa! No, no, no!
-[Brooklynn grunting]
-Why aren't we moving?
-Ben, what did you do?
-Nothing! It just stopped!
[all screaming]
-[screaming continues]
-[Yasmina] What's going on?
It's the emergency break!
-I have an idea.
-Darius!
You're strong?
Like, really, really strong?
What are you doing?
[exhales] Catch me! [yells, grunts]
Whoa!
[grunting]
It's working. It's working!
[roars]
[all screaming]
[thudding]
[heart monitor beeping]
Hey, Dad. [chuckles]
You won't believe it,
but there are all these rumors online
that Jurassic World
will announce a new dinosaur
by the end of the year!
[chuckles] Oh, really?
What do you think it'll be?
Maybe they'll finally make an anchiornis.
Or maybe a carnotaurus. Heh!
Dad, they've already got that.
And whatever you do,
do not ask me if I'm "carno-sure-us."
[chuckles]
Of course.
You're right.
You really do know it all.
Not everything.
That's why this Jurassic World trip
is gonna be awesome.
And we're going in May
when they're doing all the hatchery tours!
-Darius--
-I've planned the whole thing out.
Where the lines are short
so you won't get too tired,
where there are benches
for you to take breaks--
D-Man, about the trip...
Dad.
Don't say it.
You're gonna get better.
You have to get better.
I-- I need you to get better.
[Dad] I'm tryin', son.
There's a lot of things
we were supposed to do together.
So many things.
That we can still do.
Listen to me.
This life, it doesn't always go your way.
Things fall apart.
But what matters is how you choose
to keep moving forward.
What matters is that you keep goin'
for the people who need you most.
That's... that's the promise we make
every day we get.
That despite all the hardships...
you never give up.
Then you aren't either.
We're doing this together.
No more "dad speeches," okay?
Heh. Fair enough.
[sighs]
I should know better
than to argue with you.
You'll see, Dad.
We're gonna make it to Jurassic World
and it's gonna be perfect.
It has to be.
[heart monitor beeping echoes]
[grunts]
[groans]
[inhales, gasps]
-[Ben] Oh, ow.
-[Brooklynn grunts]
-Are you okay?
-[all groaning]
-[Kenji grunts]
-[roaring]
Where the heck is that thing?
[whimpers] It's coming.
Shh! It could be anywhere.
The observation tower was that way?
Or was it that way? I... [sighs]
Okay, I'm sorry, but I--
[gasps]
[gasps] Where's-- No, no.
My necklace, I left it in my bunk!
-[roaring]
-[all gasp]
We've got slightly bigger problems than--
We have to run. Now!
[all panting]
Everything will be fine
when we get back to camp.
Ah! [pants]
Faster!
[gasps]
[all gasp]
[Darius gasps]
[creaking]
Dave, Roxie, the other workers,
they must've all gotten away.
[gasps] Not all of them.
[gasps]
Hello?
Hello!
Can anybody--? [grunts]
[sighs]
We're on our own.
-Give me my phone!
-What?
I don't care about you
sneaking into Dr. Wu's lab,
I don't care about whatever you did
with the skin samples you took
from the sinoceratops--
-What?
-What skin samples?
-What were you doing in Dr. Wu's lab?
-I don't even care that you stole it now.
All I wanna do is call for help!
Where is it?
Uh, I...
[Sammy whimpers]
I...
I don't know what you're talkin' about!
Skin samples? Sneaking into labs?
You made up some crazy thing
in your own dang head!
Hey, back off.
Not everything revolves around you
and your phone!
It isn't Sammy's fault you lost it!
Would you guys please keep it down?!
-There's a big--
-A big, scary dinosaur?
Of course there's a big, scary dinosaur!
There's always a big, scary dinosaur!
And you're always a big-mouthed jerk!
-Give it back!
-Back off!
Yeah? Well, at least I don't play
with crayons!
What is your problem with me?
I'm trying to get us,
-all of us out of this mess!
-My necklace. No.
-[Sammy] I didn't lie to you about it!
-[creaking]
-[Brooklynn] Just stop!
-[Ben] Money's not gonna help any of us!
No one is getting out of here! [pants]
We just saw people get eaten!
We're alone, we're defenseless.
We're dead.
-[all scoff]
-I can't believe this.
[Darius] We're not giving up!
I get it. It's scary.
This wasn't how it was supposed to be.
Things aren't always gonna go your way.
Life is messy and sometimes...
things fall apart.
But that's okay
because when that happens,
we pick up the pieces and keep going.
And we never give up.
-What about your necklace?
-It's not important.
I've got the memories right here.
What are we supposed to do?
[Darius] Get south to the park. Get help.
And the only way we'll make it
is if we do it together.
We're a team or we're nothing at all.
Or, you know, we don't go back
into the jungle.
You can wait
for the negligent babysitters,
but I'm with Darius.
Wait, really?
Dude, there's no way I survived
a dinosaur attack...
-[grunts]
-Wah!
...just to be taken out
by cheap camp debris.
Kenji ain't goin' out like that.
We're going south.
The rest of you coming or what?
I'm in.
We're in, too.
[Ben] Um, but guys?
[gasps]
[sighs]
It's just one dinosaur.
[snarling]
[roars]
[theme music playing]